

CONTACT

4144 Saint Antoine Street, Apt A, Detroit, MI 48201 +1 (662)-370 9875

hi1387@wayne.edu

SKILLS

- Strong knowledge of physical and analytical chemistry
- Microsoft office (MS Word, MS Excel, PowerPoint)
- Ability to handle multiple tasks/projects simultaneously
- Advance mathematical skills
- Strong communication and presentation skills
- Ability to adopt to the organizational culture
- Great collaboration and teamwork skills

WIDANA KANKANAMGE DAYANGANI NIROSHA KAUSHALYA

PROFILE

Professionalism and going that extra mile is the philosophy that is on pursuit throughout my life and career, which has brought dynamism to the profile. Sheer hard work, determination and grit have kept me always on the top where it matters. I have instilled a strong belief in me that nothing is impossible with the correct adoptive attitude. Unflinching work ethics in practice have always made me to exceed all expectations of an organization. Killer instinct to counter competition always brings expansions of own market share. Versatility has been brought into the profile through inspiring leadership Qualities, and highly commended communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant Mississippi State University, United States of America

2018 - 2020

Responsibilities:

- Assisted with classroom instructions and provided support and quidance to undergraduate students
- Maintained a supportive, safe and clean classroom environment
- Assisted faculty members with classroom instructions, exams, record keeping, and other miscellaneous projects
- Prepared chemicals in teaching laboratories

Teaching Assistant
University of Kelaniya, Sri Lanka

2015 - 2017

I was able to work in different laboratories: Analytical, Physical, Environmental, Organic and Synthetic Chemistry and Functional Biochemistry Laboratories

Responsibilities:

- Designed and coordinated the scheduling laboratory experiments
- Prepared compounds, tested solutions and reagents to conduct tests and experiments, then advising and coordinating on test procedures
- Delegated tasks to other teaching assistants

NON-COURSE

EXPERIANCE

- Research Symposium judge, undergraduate Research Studies, Mississippi State University (2019)
- Committee member of the Graduate Chemical Association, Mississippi State University (2018 -2020)
- Committee member of the Society of Chemistry, University of Kelaniya (2011/2015).
- Actively participated for Chemistry Day done by Chemical society, University of Kelaniya (2014).
- Delivered a presentation "life and consumer acceptability of selected seasonal fruits by dehydration processes" at Research Service Centre, University of Kelaniya (February 2015).
- Resource person in Practical Training Program for General Certificate of Education, Advance Level, Bio-systems Technology Teachers Conducted by Ministry of Education, Sri Lanka and Research Service Centre, University of Kelaniya (June 2015).
- Member of the organizing committee, 5th Workshop on Photovoltaics: The Need, Their Science and Applications, University of Kelaniya (January 2016).
- Actively participated in organizing of "International Research Symposium of Pure and Applied Sciences" (2016)
- Active member in nature club, University of Kelaniya (2012).

EDUCATION

Master of Science Degree in Chemistry

Mississippi State University, United States of America

2018 - 2020

GPA 3.60 / 4.00

Bachelor of Science (Special) Degree in Chemistry
University of Kelaniya, Sri Lanka

2015 – 2017
GPA 3.45 / 4.00

Core Subjects: Chemistry (Major), Mathematics, Computer Science

PUBLICATIONS

2020 - Acharya, B.; **Kaushalya, W. K. D. N.;** Martens, J.; Berden, G.; Oomens, J.; Patrick, A. L. A Combined Infrared Ion Spectroscopy and Computational Chemistry Study of Hydroxyproline Isomers. Journal of American Society for Mass spectrometry, 2020, https://doi.org/10.1021/jasms.0c00061.

2017 - Kaushalya, W. K. D. N., Weerasooriya M. K. B., Development of Value Added Product from Cashew Apple using Dehydration Processes. Journal of Scientific & Industrial Research, 2017, http://nopr.niscair.res.in/handle/123456789/39823

2015 - Kaushalya W. K. D. N., Weerasooriya M. K. B., Development of Ready to eat Cashew apple snacks with improved consumer acceptability and long shelf life, International Conference on Multidisciplinary Approaches, Faculty of Graduate Studies, University of Sri Jayewardenepura, Sri Lanka, (2015), pp 236.

REFREES

Dr. Amanda Patrick

Assistant Professor

Department of Chemistry, Mississippi State University, United States of America

Telephone: +1 (662) 325-7606

E-mail: apatrick@chemistry.msstate.edu

Dr. Sean Stokes,

Assistant Clinical professor,

Department of Chemistry, Mississippi State University, United States of America

Telephone: +1 (662) 325-0174

E-mail: sstokes@chemistry.msstate.edu